Egor Philippov FULL STACK ENGINEER

W: egor.philippov.ca
G: github.com/lone-cloud
E: egor@philippov.ca

ABOUT

A passionate technology professional with the ability to work on all parts of an application, be it on the server, browser or mobile.

Highly adaptable, innovative and articulate communicator specializing in building world class web applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PANASONIC

SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER

Remote Apr 2020 – Aug 2024

- Systems design and full stack development for <u>yohana.com</u>, portal.yohana.com and app.yohana.com.
- Full stack development using Next.js (TypeScript + React + Node.js) and backend development of gRPC microservices using Micronaut (a Kotlin framework).
- Establishing and enforcing best software development practices (strong typing, linting, spell checking, etc..), enforcing accessibility guidelines, running interviews, CI/CD implementation and general build + deployment automation.
- Wrote and automated the automatic re-publishing of a library for sharing the protobuf typing between Kotlin and TypeScript projects.
- Implemented rich, HTML-based, litmus-tested email templates and a related client library.
- Full stack development and prompt-engineering of AI-based assistants using GPT-40 with custom functions for real-time data fetching.
- Frontend development using React (Gatsby) of <u>cloudkitchens.com</u> and various internal web-based tools that were primarily used for new customer on-boarding and

CLOUDKITCHENS

Remote Dec 2022 – Dec 2023

GOOGLE

Remote & Palo Alto, US Oct 2016 – Apr 2020

FULL STACK ENGINEER

marketing research.

- Full stack development of various various enterprise applications for Google Store and Nest including enterprise.nest.com, hvac.nest.com and home.nest.com/login.
- Full stack development using Ember.js and Golang.

NIDRATECH LTD

Vancouver, Canada Aug 2015 – Present

TECHNICAL LEAD

Lead the development of several web, mobile and browser applications:

- <u>score.restaurant</u> A web app for searching the rankings of restaurants based on health inspection reports.
- <u>huegasm.com</u> A browser extension, web and mobile app for controlling Philips Hue lights and synchronizing them with the beat of your music.

ABSOLUTE SOFTWARE

Vancouver, Canada Jan 2014 – Oct 2016

OPENBET TECHNOLOGIES

Burnaby, Canada Aug 2012 – Jan 2014

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

 Full stack development using Java EE and Ember.js of enterprise web applications for remote management of company owned mobile devices.

JUNIOR - INTERMEDIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Full stack development using TCL and Backbone.js of an online casino and sports betting portal for a Canadian casino at playnow.com.
- Special emphasis was put into database performance and high concurrency.

SAP INTERN SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Vancouver, Canada Sept 2009 – Sept 2010 Java development of installation software for a business intelligence suite (Crystal Reports).

EDUCATION

SIMON FRASER UNIVERSITY

Burnaby, Canada Sept 2008 – Apr 2012

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTING SCIENCE

• Concentration in distributed systems.